# Chia-Hsuan (Michael) Lee

☐ +1 669-204-2924 • ☑ chiahsuan.li@gmail.com in chiahsuanlee, ☆ chiahsuan156.github.io

#### Research interests:

My research interests are deep learning/machine learning and their applications in natural language processing. My recent research interests are open-domain question answering, dialogue systems and semantic parsing. Broadly speaking, I am interested in language understanding and interpretability of deep learning models.

#### **Education**

University of Washington

Seattle, U.S.

PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering,

Sep, 2019 –

Natural Language Processing Group, Advisor: Professor Mari Ostendorf - with Fellowship Fundings

**National Taiwan University** 

Taipei, Taiwan

Master, Computer Science,

Sep. 2017 - June, 2019

Advisors: Profs. Lin-shan Lee and Hung-Yi Lee

**National Taiwan University** 

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S., Electrical Engineering, Advisor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee Sep, 2012 - Jan, 2017

## **Research Internship**

 Al Research intern, Machine Translation Team, Google, Mountain View, CA, June-Sep 2021 (expected)

Pretraining for Multilingual Multi-task Benchmark.

- Al Research intern, NLP group, Microsoft, Redmond, WA, June-Sep 2020 Cross domain text-to-SQL parsing.
- NLP intern, Siri Team, Apple Inc., Cupertino, CA, July-Sep 2019
   Multilingual language modeling

## Publications (All as the First Author)

- [1] "KaggleDBQA: Realistic Evaluation of Text-to-SQL Parsers" ACL2021
- [2] "Cross-Lingual Transfer Learning for Question Answering" [Link]
  - Incorporate adversarial learning to learn domain-invariant feature representations between languages.
  - $\bullet$  Successfully bootstrap knowledge from English and achieve SOTA over a Chinese QA corpus, which outperforms previous best model by over 30 % F1 score.
- [3] "Spoken SQuAD: A Study of Mitigating the Impact of Speech Recognition Errors on Listening Comprehension" Interspeech 2018 [Link]
  - Successfully construct a challenging spoken question answering(QA) dataset.
  - $\bullet$  Utilize phonetic sub-word units to mitigate ASR errors and consistently improve SOTA QA model by 1.4% F1 score under different levels of noises.
- [4] "ODSQA: Open-Domain Spoken Question Answering Dataset" IEEE SLT 2018 [Link]
  - Collect the largest open domain spoken QA dataset.
  - $\bullet$  Propose two data augmentation approaches: Text-to-Speech and Back-to-Back translation and improve SOTA QA model by 4% F1 score.
- [5] "Mitigating the Impact of Speech Recognition Errors on Spoken Question Answering by Adversarial Domain Adaptation" ICASSP 2019 [Link]

- Incorporate adversarial learning to adapt Reference Transcriptions domain to ASR hypotheses domain.
- $\bullet$  Outperform previous best model by 2% EM score.
- [6] "Towards Machine Comprehension of Spoken Content", IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing[Link]
  - Thorough study of QA models over two spoken QA corpora.
  - Select important sentences by using gated GRU and conduct multi-hop reasoning by long term memory component.

#### **Honors and Awards**

- o Electrical and Computer Engineering PhD Fellowship, University of Washington, Seattle
- Language Technologies Research Scholarship, Committee of Advanced Language Technologies (US\$16,000)
- o Artificial Intelligence Top Research Scholarship, Appier
- o Student Research Scholarship, Ministry of Science and Technology of Taiwan

## **Research and Teaching Experiences**

#### Graduate Researcher, Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab

Taiwan

Advisors: Profs. Lin-Shan Lee and Hung-Yi Lee,

Sep, 2017 - June, 2019

- Utilize learned phonetic representations to improve speech question answering model. [Interspeech]
- Utilize Back-to-Back translation system and Text-to-Speech system to improve speech question answering. **[IEEE SLT]**
- Propose an unified framework for cross-domain question answering and successfully achieved significant improvement on challenging cross lingual task and speech question answering task. **[ICASSP]**

Teaching Assistant Taiwan

National Taiwan University, Advanced Deep Learning [CSIE7430], Mar, 2018 – June, 2018

Design a challenging video caption generation task using CNN + RNN Seq-to-Seq.

### **Head Teaching Assistant**

Taiwan

- National Taiwan University, Machine Learning [EE5184], Sep. 2017 Jan, 2018 Organize 19 teaching assistants and create 9 assignments for 353 students including text Sentiment classification(RNN+DNN, Semi-Supervised learning), movie recommendation(Matrix Factorization, DNN), chatbot(Seq-to-Seq) and speech translation(Kaldi, Retrieval Model, Seq-to-Seq). [Course Link]
- Research Assistant, Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab

  Advisor: Prof. Hung-Yi Lee,

  Utilize learned gating function and long-term memory to improve two speech question answering corpora.

  [IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing]

## **Selected Projects**

## CSIE5130 Multimedia Analysis and Indexing

Taiwan

Sketch-based Image Retrieval across Art Styles,

2017 Sep - 2018 Jan

Perform cross-domain image retrieval across different art styles using sketches as queries via hierarchical triplet CNN and triplet margin loss.

#### **EE5047 Artificial Intelligence**

Taiwan

Vision-based Deep Reinforcement Learning: Playing Atari Games, 2016 Sep – 2017 Jan Analyze the strength and weakness of Deep Q Learning(DQN), DoubleDQN and DuelingDQN in Atari Games